<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Coding Journey</title>
    <link>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Coding Journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:48:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aly-bahaa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Engineering for web developers</title>
      <link>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/posts/prompt-eng/prompt-eng-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 22:48:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/posts/prompt-eng/prompt-eng-post/</guid>
      <description>🔺 Disclamer Some of the examples are taken from the course &amp;ldquo;prompt engineering for web developers&amp;rdquo; (Link in references) The model used is chatGPT 3.5 🚀 Introduction Generative AI is a cutting-edge technology that enables computers to create human-like text, opening up exciting possibilities across various applications. At the heart of this technology lies prompt engineering, the art of communicating with AI models to yield the best results. As generative AI continues to advance, understanding and mastering prompt engineering becomes increasingly crucial for everyone and especially software developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 00:09:57 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/pages/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synchronous vs Asynchronous in Web dev</title>
      <link>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/posts/post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 22:25:50 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aly-bahaa.github.io/posts/post/</guid>
      <description>What the heck is synchronous and asynchronous request? Synchronous and asynchronous requests are two distinct approaches to how a client interacts with a server. They are not only related to web development; they are widely used in different areas (such as operating systems). In this article, I will be focusing only on the context of web development.
Synchronous requests In synchronous communication, the client (e.g., a web browser) sends a request to the server,which then gets blocked waiting for the response.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
